Finding aid to the James Parker records, 1924-2005 Archives.Parker.1
The Metropolitan Museum of Art Archives
- Series I. Research, 1912-1997, n.d.; 31.0 Linear feet (72 boxes, 839 folders)
  - Subseries I.A. Card File, 1922-1933, 1943-1950, 1957-1996, n.d.; 25.0 Linear feet (60 boxes, 722 folders)
    - Painting. French. Makers (D). (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Note: Cites - Dandre-Bardon, Danloux, Jacques Louis David, Debret, Debucourt, Degault, de La Fosse, Delaporte, Delanoche, Delecluze, Delutel, Deruet, Deshayes, Despax, Despontes, Dorigny, Doyen, Dreux, Drouais, Dubois, Ducreux, Ducros, Dughet, Dumons, Dumont, Duplessis, Dunameau, Duzzeaux, Dussault, Dutemas.
    - Painting. French. Makers (E - G). (Box 44, Folder 5)
      Note: Cites - Eisen, Errard, Fabre, Favray, Filipart, Foucquet, Fournier, Fragonard, Francart, Frechou, Frédou, Froissart, Galland, Garneray, Gernier, Gauffier, Gauguin, Gauet, Gérard, Gérôme, Gervaise, Gille Colson, Girodet, Godard, Gleyre, Gobert, Gosse, Gouboud, Granet, Guenin, Guillon.
    - Painting. French. Makers (H - J). (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Note: Cites - Hallé, Hauer, Heim, Helleu, Hersent, Houasse, Huet, Huillot, Hutin, Hyne, Isabey, Jaquotot, Jeanteau, Jeaurat, Jollain, Jouvenet, Julien.
    - Painting. French. Makers (L). (Box 44, Folder 7)
      Note: Cites - Labille-Guiard, Lacroix de Marseille, Lafaye, Lafitte, de La Fosse, Lagrenée, Lagrenée le Jeune, Lagrenée l'Ainé, la Hine, Lajoue, Lallemant, Lambert, Lami, Lancret, Largillierre, Lassale, de La Tour, Laruens, Lebel, Lejeune, Lemoyne, Le Clerc, Lefèvre, Le Mettay, Le Francois Moyne, Lepeintre, Lépicié, Le Prince, Le Riche, Van Loo, Le Sueur, Levieux, Levy-Dhurmer, Loutherbourg. Contains correspondence from Jennifer G. Lovett, Sterling and Francine Clark Art Institute (1987).
    - Painting. French. Makers (M - O). (Box 44, Folder 8)
      Note: Cites - de Machy, Maecot, Mallet, Manglard, Marot, Martin, Massé, Mathieu, Mattise, Meissonier, Melling, Mencier, Mérelle, Merson, Micheux, Mignard, Moënch, Moillon, Monnoyer, Montpetit, Moreau, Mosnier, Müller, Naigeon, Natoire, Nattier, Ollivier, Oudry.
    - Painting. French. Makers (P - Q). (Box 44, Folder 9)
      Note: Cites - Paillet, Pajou, Parrocel, Pascal, Pater, Pecheux, Perronneau, Perrot, Petitot, Peyron, Peyrotte, Jean-Baptiste-Marie Pierre, Pigalle, Pillement, Polignac, Poussin, Prévost, Prud'hon, Puvis de Chavannes, Quillard.
    - Painting. French. Makers (R). (Box 44, Folder 10)
      Note: Cites - Raffet, Raguenet, Ranc, Raoux, Réattu, Redon, Redouté, Regnault, Rémond, Renoir, Restout, Trevoil, Ribot, Richard, Riesener, Rigaud, Robert, Robin, Rouget, Rousseau, Rude.
    - Painting. French. Makers (S - T). (Box 44, Folder 11)
      Note: Cites - Saint-Aubin, Saint-Non, Santerre, Schall, Sicardi, Silvestre, Slodtz, Stiemant, Subleyras, Taraval, Tardieu, Taunay, Thierrat, Tocqué, Tournières, Tremolières, Trinquesse, deTroy.
    - Painting. French. Makers (V - Z). (Box 44, Folder 12)
      Note: Cites - Valade, Valentin, Vallayer-Coster, Van Dael, Carle Vanloo, Horace Vernet, Joseph Vernet, Vestier, Vien, Vigée-Lebrun, Vignon, Vincent, Vivien, Vouet, Voiriot, Watteau, Wicar, Yvart, Zieseniss.
    - Painting. German. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Note: Cites - Graff, Gran, Heinsius, Lutke, Maulbertsch, Mengs, Menzel, Pesne, Platzer, Schaettle, Winterhalter, Zachenberg, Zick.
    - Painting. Irish. (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Note: Cites - Dixon, Howard.
    - Painting. Italian. (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Painting. Italian. Makers (A - F). (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Note: Cites - Amigoni, Andrea Appiani, Giuseppe Appiani, Batoni, Bacciarelli, Boldini, Borzone, Brunetti, Brunias, Cades, Canaleto, Capella, Casali, Castglione, Cavallino, Cipriani, Conca, Diano, Falciatore, Ferretti, Ferri, Fiorvanti, Francheschini, Fumiani. Contains correspondence to Bernadette Bigone (1990).
    - Painting. Italian. Makers (G - P). (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Note: Cites - Gallina, Gandolfi (Ubaldo, Gaetano, Mauro), Ghisi, Giani, Giovine, Guarana, Joli, Landini, Lapiccola, Ligozzi, Longhi, Lusieri, Maffei, Maratti, de Mura, Nogari, Palagi, Panini, Paradisi, Pellegrini, Piattoli, Pignatta, Politi.
    - Painting. Italian. Makers (R - Z). (Box 45, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Mixed. Cites - Raphael, Reni, Revelli, Ricci, Rocca, Rotaris, Sagrestani, Sanguineti, Serangeli, Simonini, Soldi, Tiepolo, Trevisani, Valdre, Zuccanelli.
    - Painting. P - U. (Box 45, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Polish. Russian. Scandinavian. Scottish. Spanish. Swedish. Swiss. U.S.A. Cites - Briullov, Raeburn, Roslin, Wertmuller, Kauffman, Liotard, Baskerville, Burroughs, Church, Hesselius, La Farge, Mowbray, Murray, Payne, Remington, Sargent, Tack, Trumbull. Contains correspondence from Malise Forbes Adam (1990).
    - Paper. (Box 45, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Papier maché. Quillwork. Fans. Games. Contains correspondence from Evelyn Jean Phimister, Florian Papp to Morrison H. Heckscher, M.M.A. (1985).
    - Pewter. (Box 45, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes English. French. German.
    - Presepi. (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Sales. (Box 45, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes General. English. Russian. U.S.A. Excludes sculpture. French missing.
    - Sculpture. Austrian. (Box 45, Folder 12)
      Note: Contains memorandum from Ed Rowe, M.M.A. (1971).
    - Sculpture. Belgian. (Box 45, Folder 13)
      Note: Cites - Jacques Bergé, Juste Decort, Laurent Delvaux, François Duquesnoy, Lucas Faydherbe, Gilles-Lambert Godecharle, Artus Quellinus, Peter Anton von Verschaffelt, Adriaen de Vries.
    - Sculpture. Br - D. (Box 45, Folder 14)
      Note: Includes Brazilian. Canadian. Chinese. Czechoslovakian. Danish. Dutch (A - Z, mixed). Cites - Bertel Thorvaldsen, Hendrick de Keyser, Adriaen de Vries, Artus Quellinus, Jean Baptist Xavery.
    - Sculpture. English. Makers (A - C). (Box 45, Folder 15)
      Note: Includes Francis Chantry. John and Henry Cheere.
    - Sculpture. English. Makers (D - L). (Box 46, Folder 1)
      Note: Cites - Anne Seymour Damer, John Flaxman, John Gibson, Sir Alfred Gilbert, Joseph Gott, Hubert Le Sueur.
    - Sculpture. English. Makers (M - R). (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Nollekens. Roubiliac. Rysbrack.
    - Sculpture. English. Makers (S - Z). Various. (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Mixed. Eskimo. Finnish.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (A - Ba). (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Adam (Lambert-Sigisbert, Nicolas-Sebastien, Jacob-Sigisbert). Cites - Allard, Allegrain, Francois Anguier, Michel Anguier, D'Antoine, L'Archevêque, Arcie, Arnaud, Attarge, Attriet, Aubé, Aubert, Aubry, Auger, Augustini, Auxenfants, Barbédienne, Bardou, Barois, Barre, Barrezat, Barrois, Bartholdi, Bartholomé, Barye.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Be - Bos). (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Boizot. Cites - Beaupre, Beauvais, Beauvallet, Becouerel, Bellanger, Benoist, Bergé, Bernard, Bernini, Berruer, Berthelot, Blondeau, Bertier, Bertrand, Besançon, Beurdeley, Biard, Biardeau, Bienaimé, Biennceis, Blasset, Blave, Balvier, Blezer, Bocciardi, Bocquet, Boichot, Boiston, Bonnard, Bonnassieux, Bontemps, Boquet, Bosio.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Bou - Bu). (Box 46, Folder 6)
      Note: Cites - Bouchardon, Boucher, Bourdelle, Bourdin, Bousseau, Bovy, Boyer, Brachard, Brenet, Breton, Bridan, Broche, Buhot, Buirette. Contains 1 slide.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Ca). (Box 46, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Caffieri. Carpeauux. Cites - Carbonneaux, Carlier, Carrier-Belleuse, Carriès, Cartellier, Castex, Cauvet, Cavellier, Cayot.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Ch - Cle). (Box 46, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Chinard. Cites - Charlle, Chanou, Chapu, Charles, Charlier, Charny, Charpentier, Chastel d'Aix, Chaudet, Chauveau, Chenais, Chenillon, Chéret, Clérion, Clésinger, Cleve.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Clodion). (Box 46, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Claude Michel, called Clodion. Contains correspondence with Dr. Grgo Gaumlin (1970).
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Col - Cou). (Box 46, Folder 10)
      Note: Cites - Collas, Collet, Collot, Colombe, Corbet, Charles-Henri-Joseph Cordier, Henri-Louis Cordier, Corneille, Cornu, Cortoto, Cossin, Costa, Cotton, Couasnon, Coudray, Coulonuon, Courrige, Couriger, Cousin, Guillaume Coustou, Nicolas Coustou, Guillaume II Coustou.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Coy - Cyf). (Box 47, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Coysevox. Cites - Coypel, Cressent, Cros, Crozatier, Cruchet, Cyfflé.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Da). (Box 47, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Dalou. Dantan. Daumier. Cites - Damerat, Dardel, d'Angers.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (De). (Box 47, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Desjardins. Cites - Debay, Debraux, Debut, de Cock, Defernex, Degas, Dejouz, Delabarre, Delaistre, Delaporte, Delaplanche, Delarue (see La Rue), Delarche, Delaville, Demontreuil, Denizot, Depiereux, D'Epinay, Derbais, Desbeoufs, Debois, Deschamps, Descomps, Desenne, Deseine, Desmoulins, Despiau, Devéche. Contains correspondence from Richard A. Bourne, Richard A. Bourne Co., Inc. (1974).
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (D'h - E). (Box 47, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Dumont. Cites - D'Huez, Diébolt, Doré, Drouet, Jean Dubois, Paul Dubois, Dubut, Duchamp-Villon, Dudot, Duhez, Dumandré, Dupasquier, Duplessis, Dupré, Durenne, Duret, Duseigneur, Duval. Espercieux.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (F). (Box 47, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Falconet. Foucou. Cites - Faivre, Falguière, Falize, Fesse, Feuchère, Feuillet, Fèvre, Fiquet, Flamen, Fontelle, Forain, Fornier, Franceschi, Francin, Francis, Francois, Fratin, Fredeau, Frémiet, Frémin, Froger.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (G). (Box 47, Folder 6)
      Note: Cites - Gardeur, Garnier, Gatteaux, Gaudier-Brzeska, Gauguin, Gautherin, Gautier, Gechter, Géricault, Gérôme, Gilis, Gillet, Girardon, Gissey, Gobert, Gois, Goujon, Granier, Gravan, Gregoine, Guérin, Gueyton, Guiard, Guibal, Guibert, Guicard, Guillain, Guillemin, Gilloux, Guméry, Guyot.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (H). (Box 47, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Houdon. Cites - Hardy, Hauré, Havery, Hébrard, Henrion, Hermand, Holain, Hongre (Le Hongre), Hottot, Houzeau, Hoyau, Hubault, Hubert, Huetz, Huez (d'Huez), Hulot, Huvé. Contains correspondence from Preston Remington, M.M.A. to Elinor M. Ryan (1933) and between Margaret C. Bissell, M.M.A. and W.K. Loomis (1932).
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (J - Lem). (Box 47, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Julien. Lecomte. Cites - Jacques, Jacquemart, Jacquet, Jaquiot, Jaley, Jannelle, Jayet, Jeannest, Joly, Julia, Klagmann, Korschann, Labarre, Labroue, Lachenais, Ladatte, Lagrellet, Laguesse, Lainé, La Macque, Lami, Lamouneux, Lange, Larche, La Rue, Laurent, Laviron, Leboiteux, Lebourg, Lebroc, Lebrun, Lecourt, Lefebure, Lefecre, Legrand, Legros, Lejeune, Le Lorrain, Lemaire, Lemire, Lemot.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Lemoyne). (Box 47, Folder 9)
      Note: Lemoyne, Jean-Baptiste, 1704-1778. Includes Louis XV. Portraits. Miscellaneous and unknown.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Lep - Lu). (Box 47, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Lepautre. Cites - Leraistre, Lerambert, Leonard, Lequesne, Leriche, Leroy, Lestache, Lesueur, Levasseur, Levieux, Lhuillier, Liance, Locret, Lorta, Lucas.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Ma - Mar). (Box 47, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Marin. Marsy. Cites - Magnier, Maindron, Mallet, Maniere, Mansart, Mansion, Manessier, Marchand, Marest, Marier, Maroton, Marot, Marquet de Vasselot, Martin.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Mas - Mir). (Box 47, Folder 12)
      Note: Cites - Maseret, Masson, Mauber, Mazeline, Meissonnier, Mérard, Mercié, Meunier, Mézières, Michallon, Michaut, Michel, Mignot, Millet, Milhomme, Miroy.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Mo - Mu). (Box 47, Folder 13)
      Note: Includes Moitte. Mouchy. Cites - Moine, Martin-Claude Monot, Pierre-Etienne Monnot, Montigny, Moreau, Mouret, Mouton, Mucha.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (N - O). (Box 48, Folder 1)
      Note: Cites - Nadauld, Nanteuil, Nanques, Navellier, Neufforge, Nini, Normain, Noyel, Oger, Obstal, d'Orléans, d'Orsay.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Pajou). (Box 48, Folder 2)
      Note: Pajou, Augustin, 1730-1809. Contains correspondence from A. Ekstrom to Preston Remington, M.M.A. (1930).
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Pe - Pic). (Box 48, Folder 3)
      Note: Cites - Pelle, Pelletier, Petit, Petitot, Pfaff, Picault.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Pigalle). (Box 48, Folder 4)
      Note: Pigalle, Jean-Baptiste, 1714-1785.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (Pig - Q). (Box 48, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Pilon. Puget. Cites - Pigard, Pineau, Pitue, Plumier, Pirier, Pissant, Pollet, Pompon, Poncet, Poultier, Poussin, Pradier, Préault, Prieur, Prou, Quénard.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (R). (Box 48, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Renoir. Rodin. Roland. Rude. Cites - Rachette, Ramey, Raon, Rascalon, Raynaut, Regnaudin, Renaud, Revel, Ricaud, Rivière, Robert, Robillon, Rochet, Roettiers, Roguet, Roncourt, Rosset, Rouillard, Rousseau, Royer, Rozet, Ruxthiel.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (S). (Box 48, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Saly. Sarrazin. Cites - Samson, Sauvage, Scie, Seigneur, Seurre, Sigisbert, Simart, Slodtz, Stouf, Sluter, Soitoux, Susse, Suzanne.
    - Sculpture. French. Makers (T - V). (Box 48, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Thomire. Vassé. Cites - Tassaert, Taunay (Taunay le Jeune), Tavaud, Taveau, Tessier, Thelot, Théodon, Thiébaut, Thierry, Toro, Tournier, Toussaint, Toussin, Triqueti, Truphème, Tuby, Valois, Van Cleve, Varin, Vast, Verberck, Veyrier, Vietti, Vigier, Vinache, Visseaux, Vital-Dubray, Vitoz.
    - Sculpture. French. [Various]. (Box 48, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Mixed. General. Church (tombs). Fountains. Garden. Indexes. Louvre. Louis XIV. 19th century. Pedestals. Renaissance. Sphinxes. Theatre.
    - Sculpture. German. (Box 48, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Dietz. Mixed. Cites - Asam, Barlach, Boeck, Boos, Braun, Brokof, Egell, Fischer, Flotner, Gerhard, DeGroff, Gunther, Hagehauer, Heschler, Jorhan, Kern, Kirchmayer, Krumper, Lehmbruck, Nahl, Permoser, Petel, Pinder, Rauch, Riemenschneider, Schadow, Schwanthaler, Straub, Tieck, Vischer, von der Putt, Wagner.
    - Sculpture. Gr - Ir. (Box 48, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Greek. Hungarian. Irish.
    - Sculpture. Italian. (Box 48, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Roman (antique).
    - Sculpture. Italian. Makers (A - Be). (Box 48, Folder 13)
      Note: Cites - Albacini, Alavoine, Algardi, Ammanati, Angelini, Angelis, Arrigucci, Antico, Bandinelli, Banatta, Bartholdi, Bartolini, Bastianini, Begarelli, Benaglia, Beltrami, Benvenuti, Bernini, Bertos, Bertrano, Bessaglia.
    - Sculpture. Italian. Makers (Bo - C). (Box 49, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Bologna. Brustolon. Canova. Cites - Boccianai, Bolina, da Bonazza, Bongiovanni, Bonicelli, Boschi, Bracci, Brucciani, Bugotti. Caffa, Calcagni, Cali, Callani, Camoi, Cametti, Campagna, Cappiello, Caproni, Canlini, Candelli, Cannadovi, Cartari, Cassetti, Castiglioni, Cattaneo, Cavaceppi, Cellini, Ceracchi, Collino, Clerici, Colombo, Comolli, Cornacchini, Corradini. Contains correspondence from Preston Remington, M.M.A. to Daniel Bartlett (1930).
    - Sculpture. Italian. Makers (D - G). (Box 49, Folder 2)
      Note: Cites - Danti, da Vinci, dell Arca, del Duca, della Porta, della Robbia, della Valle, d'Este, Dossena, Dumandne, Falconet, Fancelli, Ferreno, Fanelli, Fedi, Ferrari, Ferrata, Ferrero, Ferri, Finneli, Figgini, Fiesole, Fioriti, Fortini, Francavilla, Filli, Friuli, Frullini, Gaggini, Gai, Gandolfi, Gemito, Germoni, Ghibenti, Giacometti, Giannelli, Giargoni, Giovanni, Giuliani, Gonzaga, Grossi, Grupello, Gueli, Guidi.
    - Sculpture. Italian. Makers (L - P). (Box 49, Folder 3)
      Note: Cites - Landatte, Lanzoni, Lazzarini, Leonardi, Lespignola, Lespin, Lombardi, Maderno (Maderna), Megeia, Maiano, Manfredini, Manzu, Managliano, Marcello, Manchesi, Marchetti, Marchio, Marchiori, Marinali, Marinals, Marochetti, Marsyas, Masini, Mettei, Manfredini, Mattielli, Mazza, Mazzoni, Mazzuoli, Mercandetti, Merchi, Mochi, Moderno, Montauti, Monti, Montorsoli, Moschino, Morlaiter, Mussi, Mozani, Nicoli, Nini, Novelli, Oliveri, Orazio, Pacetti, Pacilli, Pagliacetti, Palardin, Palma, Papi, Parodi, Penna, Persico, Piamontini, Piazzetta, Pierantoni, Pinelli, Pio, Pisano, Pisani, Pistrucci, Plura, Pogliaghi, Pollaiuolo, Ponsonelli, Pradel, Prestinari, Puzzi.
    - Sculpture. Italian. Makers (R - S). (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Note: Cites - Raffaelli, Raggi, Rastrelli, Riccio, Francesco Righetti, Righi, Roccatagliata, Romanelli, Romagnesi, Rosso, Rusconi, Salvi, Sammartino, Sanmartino, Sansovino, Scandellari, Schiaffino, Serpotta, Silici, Sirigatti, Soldani, Solari, Spalla, Spinazzi, Stanetti, Strazza, Susini.
    - Sculpture. Italian. Makers (T - Z). (Box 49, Folder 5)
      Note: Cites - Tabacchi, Pietro Tacca, Tadolini, Targone, Antonio Tarsia, Tenerani, Torretti, Torrigiani, Trentanove, Tribolo, Triscornia, Vaccaro, Valadier, Vanelli, Vanni, Verocchio, Villa, Vismara, Vittoria, Volpini, Voyez, Zocchi, Zoffoli.
    - Sculpture. Italian. Mixed. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Sculpture. M - R. (Box 49, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Mexican. Polish. Portuguese. Romanian. Russian.
    - Sculpture. S - Y. (Box 49, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Scottish. Spanish. Swedish. Swiss. U.S.A. (Hawaiian). Venezuelan. Yugoslavian.
    - Shellwork. (Box 49, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Belgian. English. French. German. Italian.
    - Silver and gold. A - D. (Box 50, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Canadian. Chinese. Czechoslovakian. Danish. Dutch. Contains 2 slides.
    - Silver and gold. English. (Box 50, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes A - Z. Mixed.
    - Silver and gold. French. Silver. (Box 50, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Louis XIII. Louis XIV. Régence. Louis XV. Louis XVI. Empire. Restoration. Second Empire. Contains 28 photographs from 1968 Verlet lecture on service d'Orléans.
    - Silver and gold. French. Silver. Makers (A - C). (Box 50, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Auguste. Ballin. Barthelemi. Besnier. Biennais. Boullier. Brichord. Cahier. Charpenat. Chéret. Christofle. Cousinet.
    - Silver and gold. French. Silver. Makers (D - L). (Box 50, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Dapcher. Drais, Durand. Duplessis. Fannière. Fauconnier. Germain. Gillet. Giroux. Jacquard. de Launay, Nicolas. Lenhendrick, L. Loir, G.
    - Silver and gold. French. Silver. Makers (O - V). (Box 50, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Odiot. Outrebon. Ouzille. Pacot. Puiforcat. Riel. Roettiers. Trevoux. Vinsac. Contains 7 postcards from Musée des Arts Décoratifs - orfèvrerie, par J.B.C. Odio (époque Empire).
    - Silver and gold. French. Gold. (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Silver and gold. French. Snuffboxes. (Box 50, Folder 8)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Betsy Jean Rosasco (n.d.).
    - Silver and gold. G - H. (Box 50, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes German (snuffboxes). Hungarian.
    - Silver and gold. I. (Box 50, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Irish. Italian (A - Z).
    - Silver and gold. M - U. (Box 50, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Mexican. Norwegian. Portuguese. Russian. Scottish. South American. Spanish. Swedish. Swiss. U.S.A.
    - Stained glass. (Box 50, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Belgian. Dutch. English. French. German. Italian. Swiss.
    - Sundials. (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Tapestries and rugs. A - D. (Box 51, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Danish. Dutch.
    - Tapestries and rugs. English. (Box 51, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Fulham. Mortlake. Sheldon. Soho Joshua Morris. Windsor 19th century.
    - Tapestries and rugs. English. Carpets. (Box 51, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Adam. Axminster. Exeter. Moorfields. Thomas Moore. Soho. Wilton. 19th century. Scotch.
    - Tapestries and rugs. French. 16th - 17th centuries. (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Tapestries and rugs. French. 18th - 19th centuries. (Box 51, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Modern.
    - Tapestries and rugs. French. Empire - 20th century. (Box 51, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Empire. Restoration. Louis-Philippe. Second Empire. 20th century.
    - Tapestries and rugs. French. Aubusson. (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Tapestries and rugs. French. Beauvais. (Box 51, Folder 8)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Betsy Jean Rosasco (1971).
    - Tapestries and rugs. French. Gobelins. (Box 51, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Cantonnieres on curtains. Portraits and paintings. Esther and Jason series.
    - Tapestries and rugs. French. Carpets. (Box 51, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes 17th century. 18th century. Empire. Directoire. Restoration. Second Empire.
    - Tapestries and rugs. French. Carpets. Savonnerie (1 of 2). (Box 51, Folder 11)
      Note: Contains correspondence with M. Omar Vau Liefferinge (1973). Contains 2 photographs.
    - Tapestries and rugs. French. Carpets. Savonnerie (2 of 2). (Box 52, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Hangings and portières. Paravents. Portraits and paintings. Seat covers.
    - Tapestries and rugs. G - Sc. (Box 52, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes German. Irish. Italian. Norwegian. Oriental. Polish. Portuguese. Russian. Scottish.
    - Tapestries and rugs. Spanish. (Box 52, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Goya. Carpets.
    - Tapestries and rugs. Sw - U. (Box 52, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Swiss. Turkish. U.S.A.
    - Textiles. A - D. (Box 52, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes [General information on conservators]. Austrian. Dutch and Flemish. Contains memorandum from Nancy Britton, M.M.A. (1992).
    - Textiles. English (1 of 3). (Box 52, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Bed coverings. Curtains.
    - Textiles. English (2 of 3). (Box 52, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Materials. Nails. Seat furniture coverings.
    - Textiles. English (3 of 3). (Box 52, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Dressing tables (flounced). Tent rooms. Wall decoration and hangings. 16th - 19th centuries. Adam. Chippendale. Upholsterers.
    - Textiles. French (1 of 10). (Box 52, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Bed coverings. Curtains.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Tapestries and rugs. French. Carpets for carpets.
    - Textiles. French (2 of 10). (Box 52, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Dressing tables. Materials. Pékin. Toile de Jouy. Velvet and "maquette" (woolen velvet). Portière.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Furniture. French. Louis XV [6 of 6] for tables (dressing).
    - Textiles. French (3 of 10). (Box 53, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Seat covers (Louis XIV, Louis XV). Contains M.M.A. memorandum from Edith A. Standen to James J. Rorimer (1957). Contains correspondence from René Huyghe, Musée Jacquemart-André to James H. Frantz, M.M.A. (1987).
    - Textiles. French (4 of 10). (Box 53, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Seat covers (Louis XVI, Empire, Restoration, Second Empire).
    - Textiles. French (5 of 10). (Box 53, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Tent rooms. Wall hangings.
    - Textiles. French (6 of 10). (Box 53, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Woven portraits (Louis XIV, Régence, Louis XV, Louis XVI).
    - Textiles. French (7 of 10). (Box 53, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Woven portraits (Empire, Restoration, Louis-Philippe, Second Empire, Art Nouveau). Philippe de La Salle.
    - Textiles. French (8 of 10). (Box 53, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Upholsterers and "fabricants" 18th century and later (A - N). Contains correspondence from René Huyghe, Musée Jacquemart-André to James H. Frantz (1987).
    - Textiles. French (9 of 10). (Box 53, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Upholsterers and "fabricants" 18th century and later (P - V). Mixed.
    - Textiles. French (10 of 10). (Box 53, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Métiers à Broderie. Rouets.
    - Textiles. G - U. (Box 53, Folder 9)